FBI Confidential Files on Communist Activity in the Entertainment Industry and FBI Surveillance Files on Hollywood on Microfilm 6111 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
FBI Confidential Files on Communist Activity in the Entertainment Industry and FBI Surveillance Files on Hollywood on Microfilm
1938-1958
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)
6111 mf
1.56 cubic feet
15 microfilm reels
Records, microfilm.
3504715
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 26, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5898 mf: FBI Files on Highlander Folk School on Microfilm 6079 mf: FBI Files on A. Philip Randolph on Microfilm 6082 mf: FBI Files on Sacco and Vanzetti on Microfilm 6106 mf: FBI Files on John L. Lewis on Microfilm
Motion picture industry -- Political aspects -- United States -- History -- Sources; Communism -- United States -- 1917- -- Sources; Blacklisting of entertainers -- United States -- History -- Sources; Leab, Daniel J.; Lester, Robert.; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation; University Publications of America (Firm)
3504715
- Correspondence - September 1942-March 1945. (Reel 1)
  - Volume 1., 1942-1943; 1 (Reel 1)
    Scope and Contents
    September 1942-July 1943. 307 pp.: List of radical artists, writers, actors, and musicians; Communist influence in labor unions; Harry Carlisle; Communist front organizations and activities; LATSE; films of a propaganda nature; Mission to Moscow; writers' unions; establishment of American Legion Union Post [Cinema Post #561].
  - Volume 2., 1943-1944; 2 (Reel 1)
    July 1943-April 1944. 228 pp.: Mission to Moscow; films of a propaganda nature; Warner Brothers Pictures; Cinema Post #561; Northwest Section (Movie Industry), Los Angeles County Communist Party organization and membership list; Screen Writers Guild; AFL and independent unions; history of Communist infiltration; Communist front organizations; Hollywood Democratic Committee.
  - Volume 3., 1944; 3 (Reel 1)
    April 1944 cont.-August 1944. 283 pp.: Propaganda in films; Motion Picture Labor Committee for Political Action; Northwest Section (Movie Industry), Los Angeles County Communist Party organization and membership list; history of Communist infiltration; Mikhail Kalatozov; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; League of American Writers; Communist and Communist-front organizations' membership subdivided into producers, directors, writers, actors and actresses, labor, and miscellaneous; Hollywood Democratic Committee; OWI activities; War Activities Committee-OWI film productions; Motion Picture Alliance for the Preservation of American Ideals; Cinema Post #561.
  - Volume 4., 1944-1945; 4 (Reel 1)
    October 1944-March 1945. 180 pp.: History of Communist Infiltration; Communist Political Association activities; Hollywood Democratic Committee; AFL Political Action Committee activities; Cecil B. DeMille; Communist infiltration of RKO Radio Pictures@CIO Political Action Committee; CSU; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; strike activities; Herbert Sorrell.
- Correspondence - February 1945-August 1947. (Reel 2)
  - Volume 5., 1945; 1 (Reel 2)
    February 1945-June 1945. 89 pp.: Soviet request for 35mm film; The Master Race; propaganda in films; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; Hollywood Democratic Committee; OWI activities; Council of Hollywood Guilds and Unions; strike activities; Herbert Sorrell; Communist Political Association; Motion Picture Alliance; screen guilds; HICCASP; CSU.
  - Volume 6., 1945; 2 (Reel 2)
    June 1945 cont. 86 pp.: Report on Soviet influence and propaganda efforts in Hollywood. @Volume 7. June 1945 cont.-September 1945. 101 pp.: HUAC investigations; Actors' Laboratory; Motion Picture Alliance; CSU-IATSE jurisdictional strike; IATSE [AFL]; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; ICCASP; Warner Brothers Pictures studio riot; Herbert Sorrell. @Volume 8. November 1945-May 1947. 270 pp.: CSU jurisdictional strikes; IATSE [AFL]; AFL strike call; Helen Gahagan Douglas; American Youth for Democracy; Frank Sinatra; Herbert Sorrell; HUAC investigations; Tenney Committee investigations; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; HICCASP; strike activities; International Film and Radio Guild; Pale Robeson and the National Win-the-Peace Committee; Motion Picture Alliance; Communist political and election activities; labor violence; PCA; International Labor Organization (ILO) support of CSU; People's Educational Center. @Volume 9. May 1947 cont.-August 1947. 127 pp. [Documents in this file are in reverse chronological order]: House Un-American Activities Committee investigations; V.J. Jerome; Henry Wallace; CSU; name checks and Communist party members; Eric Johnston and the Motion Picture Association; PCA, Hollywood Chapter; Motion Picture Alliance. @Volume 10. August 1947 cont. 252 pp.: Report on the history, prominent individuals, and organization of Communist infiltration.
  - Volume 7., 1945; 3 (Reel 2)
    June 1945 cont.-September 1945. 101 pp.: HUAC investigations; Actors' Laboratory; Motion Picture Alliance; CSU- IATSE jurisdictional strike; IATSE [AFL]; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; ICCASP; Warner Brothers Pictures studio riot; Herbert Sorrell.
  - Volume 8., 1945-1947; 4 (Reel 2)
    November 1945-May 1947. 270 pp.: CSU jurisdictional strikes; IATSE [AFL]; AFL strike call; Helen Gahagan Douglas; American Youth for Democracy; Frank Sinatra; Herbert Sorrell; HUAC investigations; Tenney Committee investigations; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; HICCASP; strike activities; International Film and Radio Guild; Pale Robeson and the National Win-the-Peace Committee; Motion Picture Alliance; Communist political and election activities; labor violence; PCA; International Labor Organization (ILO) support of CSU; People's Educational Center.
  - Volume 9., 1947; 5 (Reel 2)
    May 1947 cont.-August 1947. 127 pp. [Documents in this file are in reverse chronological order]: House Un-American Activities Committee investigations; V.J. Jerome; Henry Wallace; CSU; name checks and Communist party members; Eric Johnston and the Motion Picture Association; PCA, Hollywood Chapter; Motion Picture Alliance.
  - Volume 10., 1947; 6 (Reel 2)
    August 1947 cont. 252 pp.: Report on the history, prominent individuals, and organization of Communist infiltration.
- Correspondence - August 1947 cont.-January 1948. (Reel 3)
  - Volume 11., 1947; 1 (Reel 3)
    August 1947 cont.-October 1947. 271 pp.: Communist propaganda pamphlet Is Communism Un-American?; Communist industrial recruiting; Industrial Subsection, Hollywood Section, Los Angeles Communist Party; trials of studio strikers; The American Crime; name checks; CSU; strikes; HUAC investigations; propaganda in films; FBI policy on previewing films for propaganda content; Ronald Reagan; Eric Johnston and the Motion Picture Association; Gary Cooper.
  - Volume 12., 1947; 2 (Reel 3)
    October 1947 cont.-November 1947. 186 pp.: History of infiltration; name checks for HUAC; HUAC Washington hearings; Charles Chaplin; Senator Claude Pepper; surveillance of and informant reports on Hollywood persons involved in the HUAC hearings; John Garfield; Communist efforts to thwart HUAC investigations; FBI previewing of films for propaganda content; John Garfield; Paul Draper; All My Sons; Arthur Miller; PCA activities opposing the HUAC hearings; Louis B. Mayer.
  - Volume 13., 1947; 3 (Reel 3)
    November 1947 cont. 93 pp.: Efforts to defend subpoenaed "Unfriendly 19"; surveillance of and informant reports on Hollywood persons involved in the HUAC hearings; Edward G. Robinson; testimony before HUAC; Martin Popper.
  - Volume 14., 1947; 4 (Reel 3)
    November 1947 cont. 111 pp.: HUAC Washington hearings and "Unfriendly 19;" National Lawyers Guild; Tenney Committee hearings; Communist influence in New York motion picture industry; Bartley S. Crum; surveillance of and informant reports on Hollywood persons involved in the HUAC hearings; Martin Popper; Screen Writers Guild.
  - Volume 15., 1947-1948; 5 (Reel 3)
    October 1947-January 1948. 320 pp.: Committee for the First Amendment; efforts to support subpoenaed "Unfriendly 19"; surveillance of and informant reports on Hollywood persons involved in the HUAC hearings; Ira Gershwins; Max Lowenthal; Martin Popper and National Lawyers Guild activities; Bartley C. Crum; Eric Johnston; John Garfield; wiretaps; American Writers Association; PCA; Hollywood "purge"; reactions to the HUAC hearings; indictment of Hollywood "10"; International Motion Picture Committee.
- Correspondence - December 1947-April 1950. (Reel 4)
  - Volume 16., 1947-1948; 1 (Reel 4)
    December 1947-May 1948. 296 pp.: People's Educational Center; PCA; screen guilds; Eric Johnston and Motion Picture Producers Committee; FBI previewing of alleged propaganda films; microphone surveillance of Benjamin Margolis; Motion Picture Association; "Hollywood 10"; Actors' Laboratory; Committee of 1000; Lynn [Lin] Root; New York theater investigations; Freedom From Fear Committee; labor situation in Hollywood; Senator Claude Peppers; Screen Writers Guild; Martin Popper; Thieves' Paradise; Motion Picture Alliance; Civil Rights Congress.
  - Volume 17., 1948-1949; 2 (Reel 4)
    May 1948 cont.-January 1949. 246 pp.: Review of book Hollywood on Trial; Abe Polonsky; wiretaps; Motion Picture Association; Hollywood Section, Los Angeles Communist Party, reorganization; Hollywood ASP and Conference for Peace; screen guilds; Sid Benson; Screen Writers Guild; "Hollywood 10"; Dore Schary; French motion picture industry; National Americanism Commission of the American Legion; RKO Radio Pictures studios; Myron C. Fagan; Cinema Educational Guild; Lester Cole lawsuit against Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM); John Howard Lawson; Civil Rights Congress.
  - Volume 18., 1949; 3 (Reel 4)
    January 1949 cont.-September 1949. 192 pp.: Cinema Educational Guild; "Hollywood 10" activities; activities calling for abolition of HUAC; Anti-Censorship Committee; Conference on Cultural Freedom and Civil Liberties; New York City ASP; social democracy and the theater; Communist infiltration of New York theater; Lester Cole lawsuit against Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM); Motion Picture Alliance; Western Peace Conference; Hollywood ASP; Civil Rights Congress; Communist infiltration in the radio industry; John Howard Lawson; Dalton Trumbo; FBI reviews of films for propaganda content.
  - Volume 19., 1949-1950; 4 (Reel 4)
    September 1949 cont.-January 1950. 184 pp.: "Hollywood 10" activities; John Howard Lawson; Dalton Trumbo; Cinema Educational Guild; Myron C. Fagan; Hollywood ASP; Continental Congress for World Peace; screen guilds; Civil Rights Congress; Lester Cole; Communist infiltration of the radio-television industry; New York City ASP.
  - Volume 20., 1950; 5 (Reel 4)
    January 1950 cont.-April 1950. 145 pp.: Los Angeles County Communist Party; National ASP; Hollywood ASP; "Hollywood 10" activities; screen guilds; Cinema Educational Guild; Myron C. Fagan; FBI reviews of motion pictures; Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace; Communist cultural activities; John Howard Lawson; Communist infiltration of legitimate theater; Actors Equity Association; Clifford Odets; Paul Draper; Hollywood ASP on hydrogen bomb issue; American-Soviet Friendship Committee; Screen Writers Guild.
- Correspondence - April 1950 cont.-April 1951. (Reel 5)
  - Volume 21., 1950; 1 (Reel 5)
    April 1950 cont.-June 1950. 79 pp.: "Hollywood 10" activities; "US Supreme Court and Hollywood 10"; Hollywood ASP on political issues; Herbert Biberman; Rockwell Kent; Cinema Educational Guild; Myron C. Fagan.
  - Volume 22., 1950; 2 (Reel 5)
    June 1950 cont. 58 pp.: Communist infiltration of legitimate theater; People's Drama, Inc.@ Little Theater Groups; Gene Kelly; lists of suspected and Communist theatrical personnel.
  - Volume 23., 1950; 3 (Reel 5)
    June 1950 cont.-September 1950. 125 pp.: "Hollywood 10" activities; Hollywood ASP support of "Hollywood 10;" Herbert K. Sorrell; Screen Writers Guild; Committee for the "Hollywood 10"; Drew Pearson allegations regarding Louis B. Mayer and cancellation of HUAC hearings on Hollywood in 1945-1946; National ASP support of "Hollywood 10"; reorganization of Los Angeles County Communist Party apparatus.
  - Volume 24., 1950; 4 (Reel 5)
    August 1950-September 1950. 152 pp.: History of Communist infiltration; John Howard Lawson; list of suspected and Communist motion picture industry personnel; Louis B. Mayer; Harry M. Warner; Korean War issue; Hollywood ASP; Screen Directors Guild; Screen Writers Guild; Motion Picture Alliance; 1947 HUAC hearings; "Hollywood 10" activities.
  - Volume 25., 1950; 5 (Reel 5)
    September 1950 cont.-November 1950. 152 pp.: "Hollywood 10" activities; Cinema Educational Guild and Myron C. Fagan; Hollywood ASP activities; Committee for the Protection of Foreign Born; Committee to Free the "Hollywood 10" activities; Dore Schary; Screen Directors Guild.
  - Volume 26., 1950; 6 (Reel 5)
    November 1950 cont. 58 pp.: Cultural Commission, Communisty Party, USA; labor unions; Actors Equity Association; Committee for the Negro in the Arts; People's Drama, Inc.@ FBI reviews of motion pictures; "Hollywood 10" activities; international motion picture affairs.
  - Volume 27., 1950-1951; 7 (Reel 5)
    November 1950 cont.-February 1951. 197 pp.: "Hollywood 10" activities; Cinema Educational Guild; labor unions; Communist front intellectual and entertainment groups; Committee to Free "Hollywood 10" activities; Hollywood ASP activities; Motion Picture Industry Council; screen guilds; anti-Communist activities in Hollywood; Korean War issue; Dore Schary; New Playwrights, Inc. People's Drama, Inc.@ An Enemy of the People; Edward Dmytryk; Los Angeles Committee for the Protection of Foreign Born; FBI reviews of motion pictures.
  - Volume 28., 1951; 8 (Reel 5)
    February 1951 cont.-April 1951. 200 pp.: HUAC investigations and hearings; National ASP; Hollywood ASP protest activities; Herbert Biberman; Communist front intellectual and entertainment groups; Gale A. Sondergaard; Motion Picture Alliance and John Wayne; Cinema Educational Guild; CSU; Herbert K. Sorrell; Edward Dmytryk; Screen Writers Guild.
- Correspondence - April 1951 cont.-July 1952. (Reel 6)
  - Volume 29., 1951; 1 (Reel 6)
    April 1951 cont.-June 1951. 218 pp.: HUAC investigations and herings; Meta Reis Rosenberg; Los Angeles County Communist Party membership; Cinema Educational Guild; National ASP's anti-HUAC activities; Motion Picture Alliance; American Guild of Variety Artists; informant reports; Hollywood Communists in Mexico; Myron C. Fagan. Volume 30. June 1951 cont. 56 pp.: Labor unions; National ASP activities; American Federation of Musicians, Local 802; Communist front intellectual and enteratinment groups; American National Theater and Academy; Huac investigations and hearings; Union Films.
  - Volume 31., 1951; 2 (Reel 6)
    June 1951 cont.-September 1951. 155 pp.: HUAC investigations and hearings; Hollywood ASP; Steve Nelson Case and the Civil Rights Congress; Herbert Biberman; John Howard Lawson; Korean War issue.
  - Volume 32., 1951-1952; 3 (Reel 6)
    September 1951 cont.-March 1952. 183 pp.: National Americanism Commission of the American Legion; list of motion pictures containing Communist or "fellow traveler" motion picture personnel; HUAC hearings; John Howard Lawson; Hollywood ASP activities; Negro motion picture actors and actresses; Screen Writers Guild; Screen Actors Guild; Motion Picture Alliance; American Legion support of anti-Communist activities in Hollywood; Hollywood Communist Party organization [John Reed Division] membership; HUAC Los Angeles Hearings witness list; Citizens Committee to Preserve American Freedoms.
  - Volume 34., 1952; 4 (Reel 6)
    March 1952 cont.-July 1952. 155 pp.: HUAC Los Angeles investigations and heraings; witness lists; anti-HUAC activities; Citizens Committee to Preserve American Freedoms; American Legion support of anti-Communist activities; Motion Picture Association; Paul Jarrico-RKO Radio Pictures dispute; Communist infiltration of New York theater and radio groups; Hollywood ASP activities; National Lawyers Guild, Beverly Hills Chapter; Edward G. Robinson; Hollywood ASP Equal Rights Conference for Negroes; Freedom Stage, Inc.
- Correspondence - June 1952-November 1958. (Reel 7)
  - Volume 35., 1952; 1 (Reel 7)
    June 1952-August 1952. 19 pp.: Judy Holliday; Hollywood ASP activities; Hollywood chapter, Civil Rights Congress, activities.
  - Volume 36., 1952-1953; 2 (Reel 7)
    August 1952 cont.-January 1953. 115 pp.: HUAC Los Angeles hearings; Hollywood ASP protest activities; Communist infiltration of radio-television industry; interrelation of Communist cultural activities between Los Angeles and New York City; National ASP on Korean War; Los Angeles Committee to Secure Justice in the Rosenberg Case; Motion Picture Industry Council support of HUAC; Champions of the Bill of Rights; Citizens Committee to Preserve American Freedoms.
  - Volume 37., 1953; 3 (Reel 7)
    January 1953 cont.-December 1953. 159 pp.: American Legion anti-Communist activities; HUAC Los Angeles hearings; Screen Actors Guild; witness lists; Hollywood ASP activities; law suits against motion picture industry; Independent Productions Corporation; The Salt of the Earth; Actor's Equity Association; labor unions; National ASP; congressional investigations in entertainment industry; John Howard Lawson; Lucille Ball.
  - Volume 38., 1953-1955; 4 (Reel 7)
    December 1953 cont.-March 1955. 240 pp.: Hollywood ASP activities; The Salt of the Earth; labor unions; Martin Berkeley; New York ASP; Herbert Biberman; John Howard Lawson; labor situation; Citizens Committee to Perserve American Freedoms; activities of Nwe York City FBI office; Motion Picture Alliance; gray lists issue; informant activities; Communist infiltration of radio-television industry; National ASP; reorganization of Los Angeles Communist Party's Cultural Division; Writers Guild of America; Barry Storm; The General Died at Dawn.
  - Volume 39., 1955; 5 (Reel 7)
    March 1955 cont.-December 1955. 152 pp.: Los Angeles Communist Party organization; Writers Guild of America; studio craft unions and screen guilds; Hollywood ASP activities; Fund for the Republic activities; New York ASP activities; The Salt of the Earth; Communist film reviews; list of Communists in motion picture industry; labor-studeio contract negotiations; American Legion list of Communists in motion picture industry; IATSE; HUAC hearings; Association of Motion Picture Producers, Inc.@ Communist ghost writer allegations; Motion Picture Alliance; American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, AFL; HUAC hearings on Communist infiltration in the New York theater and radio-television industries.
  - Volume 40., 1956-1958; 6 (Reel 7)
    January 1956-November 1958. 197 pp.: John Cromwell; Los Angeles Communist Party, Cultural Division membership; Citizens Committee to Preserve American Freedoms; Musicians Committee for Cultural Freedom; Hollywood ASP activities; HUAC hearings; Independent Productions Corporation; American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, AFL; HUAC hearings on Communist infiltration in the New York theater and radio-television industries; Fund for the Republic activities; Marilyn Monroe; Storm Center; King Brothers, Inc. cover up of Communist script writers; John Howard Lawson; blacklisting issue; Arts and Research Foundation; activities of the "Hollywood 10"
- News clippings - January 1943-October 1947. (Reel 8)
  - Volume 1., 1943-1944; 1 (Reel 8)
    January 1943-February 1944. 118 pp.: Labor union activities; Mission to Moscow; Press reviews of films; David Platt's "Film Front" column--commentaries and reviews [from Daily Worker]; Motion Picture Alliance; Charles Chaplin.
  - Volume 2., 1944; 2 (Reel 8)
    March 1944-December 1944. 103 pp.: David Platt's "Film Front" column--commentaries and reviews [from Daily Worker]; The Negro Soldier; labor union activities; Hollywood Democratic Committee; Seventh Cross; Motion Picture Alliance; Screen Writers Guild; Hollywood Writers Mobilization.
  - Volume 3., 1945; 3 (Reel 8)
    January 1945-May 1945. 102 pp.: David Platt's "Film Front" column--commentaries and reviews [from Daily Worker]; Screen Actors Guild; Uncle Remus; postwar educational film production; Soviet films; CSU-IATSE jurisdictional strike; labor violence.
  - Volume 4., 1945; 4 (Reel 8)
    June 1945-December 1945. 65 pp.: David Platt's column--commentaries and reviews [from Daily Worker]; proposed HUAC investigations of motion picture industry; Motion Picture Alliance; Cecil B. DeMille; Herbert K. Sorrell and CSU strike activities; religious and racial intolerance in motion picture industry.
  - Volume 4 (Only Documents Dated 1946)., 5 (Reel 8)
    January 1946-December 1946. 47 pp.: David Platt's column--commentaries and revews [from Daily Worker]@United Productions; screen guilds; labor-studios wage negotiations; HUAC investigations.
  - Volume 5., 1947; 6 (Reel 8)
    January 1947-June 1947. 102 pp.: David Platt's column--commentaries and reviews [from Daily Worker]; foreign film reviews; HUAC investigations and hearings; anti-Soviet films; Robert Taylor and the Song of Russias; Adolphe Menjou; Eric Johnston; Screen Writers Guild.
  - Volume 6., 1947; 7 (Reel 8)
    July 1947-October 1947. 117 pp.: HUAC hearings; House Labor Subcommittee investigations of unions; labor strife; Los Angeles "Town Meeting of the Air" [radio discussion program]; Charles Chaplin; Hanns Eisler; PCA anti-HUAC activities; "Unfriendly 19"; Jack L. Warner.
  - Volume 7., 1947; 8 (Reel 8)
    October 1947 cont. 117 pp.: Robert Taylor and Song of Russia; HUAC hearings; John Howard Lawson; Adolph Menjou; John Weber espionage investigation and Chalmers "Slick" Goodlin; Rupert Hughes; Paul V. McNutt; Committee for the First Amendment.
  - Volume 8., 1947; 9 (Reel 8)
    October 1947 cont. 113 pp.: Reactions to HUAC hearings; HUAC hearings; Humphrey Bogart; Paul V. McNutt and the Motion Picture Producers Association; Eric Johnston; Senator Claude Pepper; Walt Disney; "Unfriendly 19"; Committee for the First Amendment.
- News clippings - October 1947 cont.-March 1949. (Reel 9)
  - Volume 9., 1947; 1 (Reel 9)
    October 1947 cont. 102 pp.: Reaction to HUAC hearings; HUAC hearings; John Howard Lawson; Eric Johnston; Dalton Trumbo; labor strikes; Roy M. Brewer; Lauren Bacall.
  - Volume 10., 1947; 2 (Reel 9)
    October 1947 cont. 81 pp.: HUAC hearings; reaction to HUAC hearings; atomic bomb spies and alleged Hollywood Communists; Emmett Lavery.
  - Volume 11., 1947; 3 (Reel 9)
    November 1947. 98 pp.: Reaction to HUAC hearings; "Hollywood 10" contempt hearings; Committee for the First Amendment; Lauren Bacall; Screen Writers Guild; House Speaker Joseph W. Martin.
  - Volume 12., 1947; 4 (Reel 9)
    November 1947 cont. 112 pp.: Reaction to HUAC hearings; RKO Radio Pictures; blacklisting allegations; Scren Actors Guild's anti-Communist policy; Eric Johnston; Twentieth Century-Fox; "Hollywood 10"; Louis B. Mayer.
  - Volume 13., 1947; 5 (Reel 9)
    November 1947 cont.-December 1947. 92 pp.: Blacklisting of "Hollywood 10"; blacklisting of alleged Communists; The Iron Curtain; Hollywood AFL Film Council; screen guilds' anti-Communist policies; Humphrey Bogart; "Hollywood 10" activities; Eric Johnston.
  - Volume 14., 1948; 6 (Reel 9)